ba-bamail.com 2019-06-22

# Privacy policy - BabaMail

###  Privacy policy

* * *

We at Baba-Mail care about your privacy. That is why we collect and use personal data only as it might be needed for us to deliver to you our world-class services, articles, emails, and mobile applications (collectively, our “Services”). Your personal data includes information such as:

  * Email address
  * Name**
  * Gender**
  * Age**
  * Other data collected that could directly or indirectly identify you.

** This information is optional and not required for your registration **.**

Baba-Mail's Privacy Policy is intended to describe to you how and what data we collect, and how and why we use your personal data. It also describes options we provide for you to access, update or otherwise take control of your personal data that we process.

If at any time you have questions about our practices or any of your rights described below, you may reach our Data Protection Officer (“DPO”) and our dedicated team that supports this office by contacting us at [privacy@baba-mail.com](mailto:privacy@baba-mail.com). This inbox is actively monitored and managed so that we can deliver a satisfying answer and any help you may require.

### **What kind of information do we collect, and why.**

We collect information so that we can provide the best possible experience when you visit our site and/or use our Services. Much of what you likely consider personal data is collected directly from you when you:

1) Create an account (Email address, name, age, gender and other technical information that is relevant)

2) Request assistance from us via the [contact form](https://www.ba-bamail.com/contact.aspx). Or use email ([privacy@baba-mail.com](mailto:privacy@baba-mail.com)) to contact us.

3) Click any of the links sent to you by email from us to either change preferences, edit your Baba-Mail profile and/or terminate your account.

However, we also collect additional information when delivering our Services to you to ensure necessary and optimal performance. These methods of collection may not be as obvious to you, so we wanted to highlight and explain below a bit more about what these might be (as they vary from time to time) and how they work:

Cookies and similar technologies on our websites and our mobile applications allow us to track your browsing behavior, links clicked, your device type, and to collect various data, including analytics, about how you use and interact with our Services. This allows us to provide you with more relevant product offerings, a better experience on our sites and mobile applications, and to collect, analyze and improve the performance of our Services. We may also collect your location (IP address) so that we can personalize our Services.

**For additional information, and to learn how to manage the technologies we utilize, please visit our** **Cookie Policy** **.**

Data about Usage of Services is automatically collected when you use and interact with our Services, including metadata, log files, cookie/device IDs and location information. This information includes specific data about your interactions with the features, content and links (including those of third-parties, such as social media plugins) contained within the Services, Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type and settings, the date and time the Services were used, information about browser configuration and plugins, language preferences and cookie data, information about devices accessing the Services, including type of device, what operating system is used, device settings, application IDs, unique device identifiers and error data, and some of this data collected might be capable of and be used to approximate your location.

Supplemented Data may be received about you from other sources, including publicly available databases or third parties from whom we have purchased data, in which case we may combine this data with information we already have about you so that we can update, expand and analyze the accuracy of our records, identify new customers, and provide products and services that may be of interest to you. If you provide us personal information about others, or if others give us your information, we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.

### **How we use information**

We strongly believe in both minimizing the amount and kinds of data we collect and limiting its use and purpose to only that (1) _for which we have been given permission_ , (2) _as necessary to deliver the Services you purchase or interact with_ , or (3) _as we might be required or permitted for legal compliance or other lawful purposes_. These uses include:

**Delivering, improving, updating and enhancing the Services we provide to you:** We collect various information relating to your purchase, use and/or interactions with our Services. We utilize this information to:

  * Improve and optimize the operation and performance of our Services (This includes our websites and mobile applications)
  * Diagnose problems with and identify any security risks, errors, or needed enhancements to the Services in order to improve them.
  * Detect and prevent fraud and abuse of our Services and systems
  * Collecting aggregate statistics about use of the Services
  * Understand and analyze how you use our Services and what products and services are most relevant to you, and which can be improved upon.

**Sharing with trusted 3rd parties:** We may share your personal data with affiliated companies within our corporate family, with third parties with which we have partnered to allow you to integrate their services into our own Services, and with trusted third party service providers as necessary for them to perform services on our behalf, such as:

  * Serving advertisements
  * Performing analysis of our Services and customers demographics
  * Communicating with you, such as by way email or survey delivery
  * Customer relationship management.  

We only share your personal data as necessary for any third party to provide the services as requested or as needed on our behalf. These third parties (and any subcontractors) are subject to strict data processing terms and conditions and are prohibited from utilizing, sharing or retaining your personal data for any purpose other than as they have been specifically contracted for (or without your consent). In no way are these third parties allowed to make use of your information for any other purpose than mentioned.

**Communicating with you:** We may contact you directly or through a third party service provider regarding products or services you have signed up or purchased from us, such as necessary to deliver transactional or service related communications.We may also contact you with offers for additional services we think you’ll find valuable if you give us consent, or where allowed based upon legitimate interests. You don’t need to provide consent as a condition to purchase our goods or services. These contacts may include:

  * **Email** (Main communication channel)

You may also update your subscription preferences with respect to receiving communications from us and/or our partners by signing into your account and visiting “Edit Profile” page.  

If we collect information from you in connection with a co-branded offer, it will be clear at the point of collection who is collecting the information and whose privacy policy applies. In addition, it will describe any choice options you have in regards to the use and/or sharing of your personal data with a co-branded partner, as well as how to exercise those options.

If you make use of a service that allows you to import contacts (ex. using our system to import your contacts from your email accounts), we will only use the contacts and any other personal information for the requested service. If you believe that anyone has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at [privacy@baba-mail.com](mailto:privacy@baba-mail.com).

**Transfer of personal data abroad** : If you utilize our Services from a country other than the country where our servers are located, your communications with us may result in transferring your personal data across international borders. Also, when you call us or initiate a chat, we may provide you with support from one of our global locations outside your country of origin. In these cases, your personal data is handled according to _this_ Privacy Policy.

**Compliance with legal, regulatory and law enforcement requests** : We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (such as subpoena requests), to protect our property and rights or the property and rights of a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we consider to be illegal or unethical.

To the extent we are legally permitted to do so, we will take reasonable steps to notify you in the event that we are required to provide your personal information to third parties as part of legal process.

**Website analytics** : We use multiple web analytics tools provided by service partners such as _Google Analytics_ to collect information about how you interact with our website or mobile applications, including what pages you visit, how much time you spend on each page, what operating system and web browser you use and network and IP information. We use the information provided by these tools to improve our Services.

These tools place persistent cookies in your browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit our website. Each cookie cannot be used by anyone other than the service provider (ex: Google for Google Analytics). The information collected from the cookie may be transmitted to and stored by these service partners on servers in a country other than the country in which you reside.

Though information collected does _not_ include personal data such as name, address, contact information, billing information, etc., the information collected is used and shared by these service providers in accordance with their individual privacy policies. You can control the technologies we use by managing your settings through our [Cookie Policy](https://www.ba-bamail.com/privacy.aspx) or the ‘cookie banners” that may be presented (depending on URL of website visited) when you first visit our webpages.

**Targeted advertisements:** Targeted ads or interest-based offers may be presented to you based on your activities on our webpages, and other websites, and based on the products you currently own. These offers will display as varying product banners presented to you while browsing. We also partner with third parties to manage our advertising on our webpages and other websites. Our third party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about such activities in order to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests, and to measure advertising effectiveness. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click [here](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) [or if located in the European Union click [here](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)]. Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

**Third-party websites** : Our website and our mobile applications contain links to third-party websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of third-party sites. Please read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

### **How you can access, update or delete your data.**

To easily access, view, update, delete or sort your personal data or to update your subscription preferences, we have provided you with an “Edit Profile” link on every page of the website once you sign in with your email address. This link will allow you to view and edit your profile’s subscription preferences, personal details and contact details.

If you make a request to delete your personal data and that data is necessary for the products or services you have purchased, the request will be honored only to the extent it is no longer necessary for any Services purchased or required for our legitimate business purposes or legal or contractual record keeping requirements.

If you are unable for any reason to access your Account Settings, you may also contact us by one of the methods described in the “Contact Us” section below.

### **How we secure, store and retain your data.**

We follow generally accepted standards to store and protect the personal data we collect, both during transmission and once received and stored, including utilization of encryption where appropriate.

We retain personal data only for as long as necessary to provide the Services you have requested and thereafter for a variety of legitimate legal or business purposes. These might include retention periods:

  * mandated by law, contract or similar obligations applicable to our business operations;
  * for preserving, resolving, defending or enforcing our legal/contractual rights; or
  * needed to maintain adequate and accurate business and financial records.

If you have any questions about the security or retention of your personal data, you can contact us at [privacy@baba-mail.com](mailto:privacy@baba-mail.com).

### **Our Cookie Policy**

When you visit or interact with our sites, services, applications, tools or messaging, we or our authorized service providers may use cookies, web beacons, and other similar technologies to make your experience better, faster and safer, for advertising purposes and to allow us to continuously improve our sites, services, applications and tools.

We hope the information below provides you with clear and comprehensive information about the technologies we use and the purposes for which we use them, but it you have any additional questions, or require any additional information, please review our Privacy Policy, Privacy Center, or contact us at [privacy@baba-mail.com](mailto:privacy@baba-mail.com)

**Your consent**  
By continuing to use and navigate our sites, services, applications, tools or messaging, you are agreeing to our use of cookies, web beacons and similar technologies as described here in our Privacy Policy.

**What** ** _are_** **cookies, web beacons and similar technologies?**  
These technologies are essentially small data files placed on your computer, tablet, mobile phone or other device (“collectively, a “device”) that allows us to record information when you visit or interact with our websites, service, applications, messaging, and other tools. Though often these technologies are generically referred to as “Cookies,” each functions slightly differently, and is better explained below:

**Cookies** : These are small text files (typically made up of letters and numbers) placed in the memory of your browser or device when you visit a website or view a message. Cookies allow a website to recognize a particular device or browser. There are several types of cookies:

Session cookies expire at the end of your browser session and allow us to link your actions during that particular browser session.

Persistent cookies are stored on your device in between browser sessions, allowing us to remember your preferences or actions across multiple sites.

First-party cookies are those set by a website that is being visited by the user at the time in order to preserve your settings (e.g., while on our site).

Third-party cookies are placed in your browser by a website, or domain, that is not the website or domain that you are currently visiting. If a user visits a website and another entity sets a cookie through that website this would be a third-party cookie.

When you enter a website using cookies, you may be asked to fill out a form providing personal information; like your name, e-mail address, and interests. This information is packaged into a cookie and sent to your browser (Chrome, Firefox, etc.), which then stores the information for later use. The next time you go to the same website, your browser will send the cookie to the server. The message is sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.

**Web beacons:**  Small files (also called “pixels”, “image tags”, or “script tags”) that may be loaded on our sites, applications, and tools, that may work in concert with cookies to identify our users and provide anonymized data on their behavior.

**Similar technologies:** Technologies that store information in your browser or device utilizing local shared objects or local storage, such as flash cookies, HTML 5 cookies, and other web application software methods. These technologies can operate across all of your browsers, and in some instances may not be fully managed by your browser and may require management directly through your installed applications or device. We do not use these technologies for storing information to target advertising to you on or off our sites.

### **What types of cookies, web beacons and similar technologies do we use and why?**

Our cookies, web beacons and similar technologies serve various purposes, but are generally either necessary or essential to the functioning of our sites, services, applications, tools or messaging, help us improve the performance of or provide you extra functionality of the same, or help us to serve relevant and targeted advertisements. More specifically:

**Strictly Necessary or Essential:** 'Strictly necessary' or “essential” cookies, web beacons and similar technologies let you move around the website and use essential features like secure areas and shopping baskets. Without these technologies, services you have asked for cannot be provided. Please note that these technologies do not gather any information about you that could be used for marketing or remembering where you've been on the internet. Accepting these technologies is a condition of using our sites, services, applications, tools or messaging, so if you prevent these from loading we can't guarantee your use or how the security therein will perform during your visit.

**Performance** : 'Performance' cookies, web beacons and similar technologies collect information about how you use our website e.g. which pages you visit, and if you experience any errors. These cookies do not collect any information that could identify you and is only used to help us improve how our website works, understand what interests our users and measure how effective our content is by providing anonymous statistics and data regarding how our website is used. Accepting these technologies is a condition of using our sites, services, applications, tools or messaging, so if you prevent these from loading we can't guarantee your use or how the security therein will perform during your visit.

**Functionality** : These cookies, web beacons or similar technologies are used to provide services or to remember settings to improve your visit.

**Advertising** : First or third-party cookies and web beacons may be placed by our sites, applications, or tools, in order to deliver content, including product related advertisements, relevant to your specific interests on our sites or third-party sites. These technologies allow us to understand how useful our advertisements are, and improve the relevancy of the content delivered to our users.

We also utilize 3rd party service providers to assist us in delivering on the same functions, which means that our authorized service providers may also place cookies, web beacons and similar technologies on your device via our services (third party cookies). They may also collect information that helps them identify your device, such as IP-address, or other unique or device identifiers.

### **How to manage, control and delete cookies, web beacons and similar technologies**

You may block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our website or service. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies as soon as you visit our site. Please note, as further described in our Privacy Policy, we currently do not alter our practices when we receive a “Do Not Track” signal from a visitor’s browser.

Internet browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. These settings are usually found in the 'options' or 'preferences' menu of your internet browser. In order to understand these settings, the following links may be helpful. Otherwise you should use the 'Help' option in your internet browser for more details.

Please note that should you wish to withdraw your consent, at any time, you will need to delete your cookies using your internet browser settings.

**For additional information about cookies**

Useful information about cookies, including information about deleting or blocking cookies, can be found at: [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

A guide to behavioral advertising and online privacy has been produced by the internet advertising industry which can be found at: [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)

Information on the ICC (UK) UK cookie guide can be found on the ICC website section:

<http://www.international-chamber.co.uk/our-expertise/digitaleconomy>

### **Age restrictions.**

Our Services are available for purchase only for those over the age of 18. Our Services are not targeted to, intended to be consumed by or designed to entice individuals under the age of 18. If you know of or have reason to believe anyone under the age of 18 has provided us with any personal data, please contact us.

### **Changes in our Privacy Policy.**

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy and any other places we deem appropriate, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page, at least thirty (30) days prior to the implementation of the changes.

### **Data Protection Authority.**

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA) and believe we maintain your personal data subject to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), can inform us by writing to [privacy@baba-mail.com](mailto:privacy@baba-mail.com)

### **Contact us.**

If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about our Privacy Policy, our practices or our Services, you may contact our Office of the DPO by email at [privacy@baba-mail.com](mailto:privacy@baba-mail.com). In the alternative, you may contact us by either of the following means:

  * By Mail: Attn: Global Content - Office of the Data Protection Officer, Vision Exchange Building, Level 2, Territorials Street, Mriehel BKR3000, Malta.
  * By Phone: (356) 2014 5320 (Hours 9AM-5PM, Mon-Fri)

**_We will respond to all requests, inquiries or concerns within thirty (30) days._**

Last Updated: 20th of May, 2018
